<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Basic Overview on MyDevOpsTeam WorkShops</title><link>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/overview/</link><description>Recent content in Basic Overview on MyDevOpsTeam WorkShops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/overview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Agenda overview</title><link>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/overview/agenda/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/overview/agenda/</guid><description>Understand the concepts and benefits of DevOps Culture &amp;amp; DevOps Engineering, to maximize the organizations in a full potential in a technical manner.
You should be able to by the end of this workshop to:
Understand the importance of devops practices and why your organizations needs it. You should be able to apply a set of tools and choose the right set of tools for your automation. Understand how you can leverage the full potential of cloud on major cloud providers.</description></item><item><title>About mydevopsteam.io</title><link>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/overview/about-us/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/overview/about-us/</guid><description>mydevopsteam.io is a pay as you go DevOps professional service. We build, support, and transfer DevOps pipelines and infrastructure for our customers. Our mission is to send your changes to production 14x faster using our automated CICD pipeline.
mydevopsteam.io also provide community based solutions to contribute to the devops community.</description></item><item><title>DevOps Overview</title><link>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/overview/devops-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/overview/devops-overview/</guid><description>
Coming soon!</description></item><item><title>Pre-requisites</title><link>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/overview/prerequisite/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/overview/prerequisite/</guid><description>This Lab will mostly use Linux as Operating System to apply automations and scripting.
Readers must have the following pre-requisites to begin:
Linux machine or WSL (Windows SubSystem for Linux) on Windows machine. With MacOS, atleast bash or basic scripting capability. Dedication to learn new things. Basic Familiarity on a major cloud providers (atleast one of them): 3.1. AWS (Amazon Web Services) 3.2. GCP (Google Cloud Platform) 3.3. Alibaba Cloud 3.</description></item></channel></rss>