<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mydevopsteam.io workshops on MyDevOpsTeam WorkShops</title><link>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/</link><description>Recent content in mydevopsteam.io workshops on MyDevOpsTeam WorkShops</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Agenda overview</title><link>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/overview/agenda/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/overview/agenda/</guid><description>Understand the concepts and benefits of DevOps Culture &amp;amp; DevOps Engineering, to maximize the organizations in a full potential in a technical manner.
You should be able to by the end of this workshop to:
Understand the importance of devops practices and why your organizations needs it. You should be able to apply a set of tools and choose the right set of tools for your automation. Understand how you can leverage the full potential of cloud on major cloud providers.</description></item><item><title>Docker installation</title><link>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/containerization/docker/docker-installation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/containerization/docker/docker-installation/</guid><description>Installation on Linux Installation on Windows Installation on MacOS Installation on Linux To install it on linux, fireup your terminal and run:
Note: You must have atleast sudo powers! And version will differ based on your linux distro.
sudo apt update -y sudo apt install docker.io -y sudo systemctl enable --now docker Now, add your non-root user to the docker group:
export IAMUSER=`whoami` sudo usermod -aG docker $IAMUSER Let&amp;rsquo;s test it:</description></item><item><title>About mydevopsteam.io</title><link>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/overview/about-us/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/overview/about-us/</guid><description>mydevopsteam.io is a pay as you go DevOps professional service. We build, support, and transfer DevOps pipelines and infrastructure for our customers. Our mission is to send your changes to production 14x faster using our automated CICD pipeline.
mydevopsteam.io also provide community based solutions to contribute to the devops community.</description></item><item><title>Creating your first docker container</title><link>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/containerization/docker/creating-first-container/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/containerization/docker/creating-first-container/</guid><description>Pre-requisites Docker Installation Initiate your project. Create a folder called my-first-docker-project and contents folder: mkdir my-first-docker-project contents Create a file called Dockerfile: touch Dockerfile vim Dockerfile Add the following contents: FROM nginx:latest COPY contents /usr/share/nginx/html Create index.html file inside the contents folder for your static page that will be served by NGINX proxy. Run the command via: vim contents/index.html Then, add the following content:
&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE HTML&amp;gt; &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;My First Container&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;center&amp;gt; &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Welcome to my First Container&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/center&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/html&amp;gt; Build your container using the following commands.</description></item><item><title>DevOps Overview</title><link>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/overview/devops-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/overview/devops-overview/</guid><description>
Coming soon!</description></item><item><title>Pre-requisites</title><link>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/overview/prerequisite/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/overview/prerequisite/</guid><description>This Lab will mostly use Linux as Operating System to apply automations and scripting.
Readers must have the following pre-requisites to begin:
Linux machine or WSL (Windows SubSystem for Linux) on Windows machine. With MacOS, atleast bash or basic scripting capability. Dedication to learn new things. Basic Familiarity on a major cloud providers (atleast one of them): 3.1. AWS (Amazon Web Services) 3.2. GCP (Google Cloud Platform) 3.3. Alibaba Cloud 3.</description></item><item><title>The DevOps Story</title><link>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/overview/stories/the-devops-story/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/overview/stories/the-devops-story/</guid><description>This video is a story of two companies doing an e-commerce website.
The first company is doing it without DevOps and is in chaos, while the other one in a parallel world is doing DevOps and is smooth sailing.
Next is the DevSecOps End-to-End demonstration.</description></item><item><title>Containerizing golang application</title><link>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/containerization/docker/containerizing-golang-application/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/containerization/docker/containerizing-golang-application/</guid><description>What is Go? Go is a statically typed, compiled high-level programming language designed at Google by Robert Griesemer, Rob Pike, and Ken Thompson. It is syntactically similar to C, but with memory safety, garbage collection, structural typing, and CSP-style concurrency.
Prerequisite: Make CLI (GNU Make) Docker CLI Create your first golang app: Create your hello-world-go project: mkdir go-rest-helloworld cd go-rest-helloworld go mod init golang/go-rest-helloworld Create Makefile to build your go app to avoid repeatable commands: Fire up the editor and add the ff: Then, add the following content:</description></item><item><title>DevSecOps End to End Demo</title><link>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/overview/stories/devsecops-end-to-end-demo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://workshops.mydevopsteam.io/overview/stories/devsecops-end-to-end-demo/</guid><description>This video is a story of two companies doing an e-commerce website.
We&amp;rsquo;ve build a DevSecOps pipeline using 100% open source technology. Sharing this video with you so that you may adapt the process and how we did it for reference purposes</description></item></channel></rss>